Downloaded @ subs4free.club
If I had a son,
what would I tell
him as a welcome to this world?
Perhaps I would just describe
an evening, nothing else.
An evening on my boat,
this heavy, well-built freighter
which at any moment can become
a fragile, tiny shell
compared to the forces
of the sea beneath it.
I would tell him about
this man's world of mine...
the monotony of the work,
the simple food,
the rare moments of delirium in the harbors...
the beauty of sleeping under the stars.
I would tell him about that constant alertness,
towards the slightest
changes of the rambling waves
which can take your life so easily,
without any bad intention...
I would tell him about our life...
trying to control the uncontrollable...
Hey, easy now!
Keep it steady!
Got it.
Yes.
- Thank you, Tommy.
- Should I?
No, it's fine.
Here he is, sir!
Thank you Tommy.
Was there something wrong
with the food, sir?
I've got a stomachache, Habib. Again.
May I ask, is it a bloated feeling,
or is it like a stone?
Like a stone. Exactly.
What about smoking?
Not even that helps...
What is it?
Is it the seaman's illness?
I'm afraid so, sir.
I'm terribly sorry,
sir, but...
no wonder after all these years.
Well then...
You're as fit as a butcher's dog.
But I'm married.
And?
It helps.
Have you gone mad asking me
to meet you in this fancy place?
Just sit down and be quiet.
Kodor, you're nuts...
Hey!
What are you drinking?
I will have a glass of milk.
Something's wrong
with my stomach.
Aha.
But please, order something else!
Something normal.
I don't want to create a scene here.
A coffee for him!
Don't look over there and speak softly.
My business partner is betraying me
right here and right now.
I see.
No, no, no, don't look over there!
Look at me.
Make like you're chatting.
Huh? Chit-chat chit-chat...
Uhm, alright.
I've decided to get married.
And who are you going to marry?
I don't know yet. A woman.
She won't see
much of me anyway.
Hah, it's a bit tricky like that!
I could marry the first woman
who comes in through that door.
It's easy to say.
They're shaking hands.
It seems they are leaving.
The swine.
I'll make him eat his own shit!
Now, let's see!
What?
You said you'd marry
the first one to come in. Right?
Yeah...
It was just a figure of speech.
I knew you'd back out of it.
That was a close one.
You escaped by a cunthair.
Go to hell.
But tell me the truth.
This whole marriage business...
aren't you afraid?
Of what?
What if she cheats on you for example?
Won't that bother you?
It's part of the deal.
Ah! Listen...
Could you help me out?
I'm a bit short on money.
Thank you.
Ciao Jakob!
Thank you for the drink!
Forgive my intrusion.
Alright. But make it short.
Please be my wife.
I'm dead serious.
I can imagine how weird it must seem
to you that someone just...
walks up to
your table and...
Tell me something about yourself.
Quickly...
Well, I'm a sea captain.
I'm six feet tall.
Yeah I can see how tall you are.
When is our wedding?
Tomorrow?
Let's say in a week.
That sounds more realistic.
I'm quiet serious.
Don't spoil the game.
What sort of captain
did you say you are?
I haven't said yet...
Freighter. Bulk cargo, generally.
And is that interesting?
Well, it depends on the cargo.
For example, coming from...
Your name, quickly!
Captain Jakob Störr.
Lizzy! My dear!
I'm a bit late, forgive me!
Let me introduce you,
gentlemen!
Mr. Ridolfi.
Captain Jakob...
- Störr...
- Störr.
Mon fiancée.
Well...
Congratulations.
Wasn't this a bit...
sudden?
He's a sea captain,
you know.
How romantic.
A profession that breaks
women's hearts.
By the way,
you're not afraid of him?
Just a teeny little bit.
In this case may I be your witness,
my dear, as your most loyal friend?
I'm sorry my sweet, you must
come up with someone else.
Do you object to
my humble person, sir?
No.
But I don't think you'll be recovered
and back on your feet by then.
Lizzy?
See you later.
Bye.
You are
some piece of work.
So are you.
I mean, uhm...
You know what?
Let's have some food brought up,
and I'll teach you sailor's poker. Alright?
This fish is good!
I'm surprised you can get it in Paris.
It would do in any harbor tavern.
Oh, you just have a healthy appetite.
Yeah.
Did I say something funny?
No.
No. It's just that...
Never mind!
So...
Sailor's poker then?
Actually there's a special version of this.
Would you
like to learn it?
Sure. How does it go?
That's what we play when
there are ladies in our company.
Come on, tell me.
Uhm... the one who loses...
takes off a piece of clothing.
Ah, it was a stupid idea.
So that's how you pass
your time on dry land.
Good to know.
Forget it.
Let's give it a try.
I don't mind.
Alright.
So, poker goes like this...
I know how to play poker.
This is great.
I never dreamed of such
a funny wedding night.
Come now, stop sulking.
It was your idea, wasn't it?
You sure know how to kiss.
How large is your base for comparison?
Don't spoil it.
I'll be back in four months.
Would be nice if this really worked out.
Yes, it would.
Don't worry!
I'll wait for you.
This is nice.
Hello.
Hello captain.
I brought you something.
You remembered.
Of course.
Thank you.
Lizzy, finally!
Hello.
Let me introduce
our Lizzy's husband,
who is finally back from his voyage
and is able to join us.
- Good evening.
- Welcome.
So...
Let me introduce... Madeleine, Paul,
Henriette, Maurice,
Geneviève...
And so Jacques...
And Pierre! I always forget him,
I don't know why...
And so Jacques travels on the oceans,
to bring us stories that
we can't wait to hear.
Right?
That always fascinated me.
Travelling...
I'll leave you to it...
I always wanted to find out...
why a ship doesn't sink?
It's unbelievable...
I know I sound stupid, but...
the whole thing is made of iron,
plus people, cargo...
some ships even transport stones,
so how does it work?
Uhm, I'll try to explain it,
it's the law of physics.
Yes of course,
the laws of physics, but...
I don't know anything about physics.
Listen I asked him something
completely stupid...
Why ships don't sink...
Excuse me, Sir,
but well...
Kodor is here.
I'm eating,
let him wait.
Alright. I'm sorry...
Let me in, let me in... Hey!
Go on, go on! Eat!
I wouldn't want to disturb you
for all the world.
I've got some goods.
A bit of hashish.
The fella's in a bind.
You can have it cheap.
Aren't you that fella
by any chance?
Why, was somebody telling you stories?
Forget it, I'm fine.
I'm in excellent shape...
We can go halves,
I feel like being generous today.
Aren't you hungry?
You can have it.
You've got a damn good cook.
- Hello!
- Here you go, sir.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Look what came in the mail for you.
- Prefect of police?
- Can I see?
Oh, this?
A week ago...
as I was
coming home...
I was walking past a church.
When all of a sudden a man simply grabbed
my handbag and ran off.
OhM God!
Yeah.
A horrible scar-faced man.
It makes me shudder even now
to talk about it.
I can imagine!
You know what?
I'll go down to the police station
and take care of it.
Oh, no, no, don't bother with that.
What are husbands for,
after all?!
But really... Jacques!
Jacques!
How could you hit that tree
at two in the morning?
You think if you have a fancy cabriolet
the whole town is yours?
You could have killed your gal!
I see in your file that you
were dead drunk!
I don't understand... my wife...
thief...
her purse...
Paul, come over, here is a guy...
who cannot speak.
No, not mute.
He only speaks English.
Thank you.
Good afternoon, sir.
How can I help you?
Uhm, can you explain to him...
My wife's purse has been stolen...
and here is the summons.
She told me that...
Tell me, are you Mr. Ridolfi?
No.
What is this summons about?
Apparently he's the little lady's husband.
Shit...
poor guy.
What should we do?
God, we must tell him,
this is the least we can do!
Wait, I've got something for you.
Here, you are...
Jacques?
I was at the
police station.
Oh...
I...
They couldn't
find the file.
How well you dance...
You are full of suprises.
Everything alright,
mates?
Yes, sir!
Isn't Fritzi the one on duty today?
Yes, sir! But we traded shifts.
Well, he wanted to see his son.
The husband
is not home, sir...
These husbands...
It'll be blustery tonight.
Aha...
Habib...
aren't you homesick sometimes?
Well...
For your wife for instance?
You said you're married, right?
Married, oh, yes, I'm married.
I have a wife.
Young, beautiful one.
Actually not one, two!
Two?
And an old one!
We were brought up together.
She's the best, the fiercest!
And what are they doing now?
Three women without a man?
Aren't you a little worried?
No!
Come on, you can tell me.
They're behind locked doors.
My mother watches over them.
My mother's still alive, she's 92!
Don't they go stir-crazy?
Maybe they do...
but that's their problem,
not mine.
Dedin!
I didn't introduce you...
but please
meet Jacques.
Jacques, the husband of Lizzy.
And our Dedin.
At last we get a chance
to meet the old sea-dog.
I'm no more of a sea-dog
than you are a wharf rat.
Am I right?
What does the young man
do for a living?
Oh, he's a writer.
I mean...
who are you speaking about?
A writer...
He also happens to have
a wealthy uncle.
In other words,
he's a parasite.
You don't like him, do you?
I saw that you didn't like him.
But it would be
so nice if you did...
Lizzy,
you want me to like your admirer?
He's not my admirer,
you are completely insane!
You can't fool me! Come on!
You're just like
a brooding hen!
Practically feverish!
Are you comparing me to a hen?
Yes, I am.
And be glad
that's all it is, for now.
How you have changed...
You have really become so rude.
Listen, Lizzy,
after all,
he is quiet a nice young man.
We...
We could invite him over,
if you want.
I've got a job offer...
to help out an old friend
who got seriously ill.
It's a high-class pass anger ship.
To Alexandria and back.
Very posh.
You know I don't like
those frail creatures...
Somehow they make me anxious...
but...
Should I take the job?
I can take you with me,
if you want.
Ahem...
Good morning!
Welcome aboard
the Marietta!
Thank you, sir!
May I ask when Madame
is planning to arrive?
We gave the captain's quarters
a bit more of a lady's touch.
Actually,
she's not coming.
Oh, I'm sorry
to hear that.
- I hope everything's fine.
- She's fine.
Well, next time then perhaps.
Let me show you around.
Captain!
Are you coming back to us after all?
No, I'm sorry Tommy...
Oh, yes, we've heard you've changed
for a more fancy job.
It's just a one-time assignment.
I only took it because of my wife.
Oh, I see,
you bring her with you...
Come on, let me buy you a drink!
Great!
Let's get a table inside!
Thank you.
Well, Tommy!
Tell me, what's new?
Not much to tell...
We'll set sail the day after tomorrow.
The captain is some Serbian fellow.
Thank you.
You have such a
handsome uniform, sir!
That Marietta!
She's a real looker!
I went to see her...
I mean, from the outside.
They wouldn't let me on board, so...
Any news about Kodor?
He is no longer around.
He's big time now.
How so?
Last month...
customs seized a large
shipment of cocaine.
A major haul.
They locked it up
in the customs depot.
Next morning...
the whole lot was burnt.
But...
Kodor had snuck
in the night before...
and replaced it all with flour.
Sweet!
He became a real
big shot in Hamburg.
I see!
Captain! Fire! We are burning!
Sir, should we
stop the engines?
Perhaps, it is time to give
the SOS signals as well...
Continue full steam, heading west
where we can catch the rain.
We are going to burn, sir!
The deck is smouldering already!
We can't risk waiting for a rescue boat!
But!
The rain will stop
the smouldering.
Full steam, I said!
Help me!
Hey!
Get him back inside!
Stay here!
Don't let anyone out!
Shouldn't we send
the radio signals now, sir?
We wait.
It's going to rain.
But...
But what?
Well, sir,
this is a delicate ship,
with a fine, thin deck!
It is not like some cargo ship.
Sir...
Guys, come quickly!
Keep the pressure stable!
Thank you.
Don't you like it?
I've switched to another kind.
- What happened to your hand?
- We had a fire.
Oh...
Were you in any danger?
Taxi!
You are shivering.
I'm so sorry
it's impossible to get a taxi...
I don't feel very well.
Poor darling.
Well, I have a car.
Should I bring you home?
Come on, let's go.
You are tired.
You have to
get in your bed.
- Thank you. That's very kind of you.
- You are welcome.
Thank you very much,
it's so kind of you!
My pleasure.
Would you like to join me
for a tot of brandy?
I've got a very special one
from Armenia.
Oh, absolutely!
With great pleasure!
Jacques...
please...
We can go,
Maurice!
This way?
Yes.
I'm gonna check on my wife.
Here, your pills.
I'm gonna put you to bed,
alright?
What's the matter sweetheart?
Please, don't...
No...
Don't...
Stop it!
Please!
So...
- Nice car you have!
- Oh, thank you.
Actually it's not mine.
My uncle lands it to me
from time to time.
So what do you do for a living?
I do nothing.
Well, now,
that's a real answer.
And what do you live on?
Well, this is truely a mystery.
Ah, so...
it's a mistery...
Listen captain, allow me
to give you a word of advice,
as long as we are discussing
financial matters.
Why?
What do you know
about my life?
And more to the point,
what business of yours is it?
Let's not beat about the bush captain.
Alright.
I know very well
what a great shock
that accident must have
been for you.
Even if you chose not to talk about it.
Everyone knows what a...
"tour de force" it was
to save that ship.
How do you know about that?
Well I have certain naval connections.
This specifically I heard
from Lord Cunningdale.
He holds you in great esteem.
You know him?
Uhum.
Really?
Here, allow me!
Thank you!
Wait a minute!
I promised you a drink.
Shall we have a drop?
But of course!
You showed real mastery, resolving
that situation all by yourself.
All those rescue services,
they skin you alive.
But with good reason,
if you think about it.
They employ only the best.
It's only natural.
And their ships always patrol
the most dangerous zones.
Thank you.
Actually, haven't you ever
thought of working for them?
One of these rescue services?
Why?
That's a terrific idea!
You are absolutely right!
How did you ever
think of this?
How not?
The job needs courage,
experience and the ability
to make quick decisions.
Frankly, this is what
you're cut out for.
Have you ever thought of
moving to Hamburg?
Why Hamburg, of all places?
Business is on the upswing there.
You keep
hearing about it.
True.
I heard that too.
But to move there?
Why not?
You know what?
You're absolutely right.
Nothing really
ties me here.
I'm grateful for the idea!
I wouldn't have thought you possesed
such a fine business sense.
But only where it concerns others.
For myself I don't manage
nearly as well,
as you have been
good enough to observe.
I...
I didn't mean to...
But it's a pleasure to be
of service to a real hero.
The king of the ocean...
I hope you had a pleasant time.
Well...
Good night.
Captain! Is that you?
How are you?
I can't believe my eyes!
You look so strange
without a uniform.
You must be the captain's wife!
God it must be exciting!
Grete Winterhalter.
Nice to meet you!
I'll be right back.
Isn't she sweet?
She certainly is.
She told me about the fire and
about everything else.
I'm truly impressed!
And if you plan to come home late,
please, let me know.
I could offer you a spare key
to the front gate.
And this key
is for your appartment.
Welcome!
What do you think?
Could we change this furniture?
Aren't you sleepy?
No.
Shall I tell you another story?
Yes, please!
Once there was a young man,
who had been at sea since
the age of sixteen.
Imprisoned aboard his ship
for months at a time.
And yet, like any other young man...
he madly yearned to be happy.
Only he wasn't sure how to go about it.
For his life had been...
about something quite different,
about duty and hard work.
One day...
his ship put in anchor on an island,
the Island of Java.
It was evening time and the young man
strolled among the tiny huts,
alone in the cool night,
among all these people...
singing or laughing...
or just chit-chatting in the depths
of their candle-lit huts.
And he thought...
he'd arrived...
on the isle of the blessed.
He would have liked to go
inside a hut, squat in a corner.
He yearned so much
to be one of them...
that his heart nearly
burst with longing.
But...
he didn't go inside any of the huts.
And the next day...
he sailed on.
Why don't you tell me a story?
Uhm...
I'm not much good at telling stories.
Come on...
Just one!
Please.
You know...
the rescue service will be
a fine job.
I'll be away
a lot, but...
Tell me the truth now.
What pleasure do you find
in living with me?
As God is my witness,
I take great pleasure
in living with you.
That girl...
She's so beautiful.
Why don't you marry her?
Come on...
You've nothing to fear
from that child.
Young girls like her
never interested me at all.
Don't touch me.
Stop fooling Lizzy.
There's nothing between
me and that girl.
My God...
Can't you see that I'm not jealous?
What's got into you?
Is it that young man? That Dedin?
Well, as for him,
believe me he's a scoundrel.
He wanted to whisk us
off to Hamburg.
I'm just telling you so you know.
He doesn't love you.
Hey...
Now...
isn't it better to be
with the one who loves you?
You think I don't love you.
Yet you're still insisting
on keeping me.
What kind of a man are you?
Do you even have blood
in your veins?
You know what?
You're right.
I don't know why
I'm still with you...
and even if I crack my stupid
stubborn skull against the wall...
I won't know the reason why I put up
with this humiliation.
There's that girl,
who perhaps loves me.
- That's what I'm trying to tell you.
- Don't talk!
Don't breathe a word!
It's a bit late for
an evening walk, isn't it?
Excuse me?
I'll close the door
in seven minutes.
I don't like to be
woken up in the night!
All right.
That's fine, Mr... Herr Blume?
Leopold Blume.
By the way, you can have
full board, or just lunch?
You forgot to tell me
when you rented the apartment.
Ah... ah...
Lunch... Lunch is fine.
You're sure?
We can divorce,
if that's what you want.
Can I say something?
Say something.
You are a big fool.
There.
Is that alright?
And don't be cross with me.
Ah, you're such a slob!
Come here...
Stop making a fool of me...
And why?
This is how the hero is welcomed back
by the home fireside.
The fireside,
in springtime?
Come on,
stop all that
huffing and puffing,
the lover's role
is not right for you.
Oh!
And why?
You're all set.
You look handsome.
Take a look
in the mirror.
No, no.
I won't look in the mirror.
So, tell me,
why do you think
I'm unsuited for the lovers role?
Well...
Is a lovebird really like this?
Why?
What is a lovebird like?
Insolent.
What am I?
You are honest.
Don't say!
Should I be a scoundrel?
Well,
a little bit...
You don't have to be
so manly all the time!
Full steam ahead!
So you don't want
me to be manly.
Fine.
How would you like me to be?
How should I know...
act like you have ravaged
every virgin in sight...
Get the picture?
Hm...
It's useless to wait for life
to accomodate you.
You must accomodate life.
Otherwise it will punish you.
Now that I've trained you,
you can go out
and flirt a little bit.
But not too much.
Tell me, what am I doing?
Have I gone completely mad?
I know a nice little hotel nearby.
What?
Look into my eyes.
Do you really love me?
I adore you!
You don't love me.
Hey!
Grete!
Don't be foolish!
Where are you going?
At least you're not lying.
But this is important to me.
For me as well...
Look,
wait here!
I must pop into this hotel
on business.
It's only for a minute.
I love you.
I won't! Don't even dream of it!
Thank you!
What took you so long?
Didn't I tell you to hurry?
You see, now it's too late.
- What do you mean, it's too late?
- What do you mean, what do I mean?
What were you thinking?
You imagine all Hamburg
is waiting for your arrival?
The job has been taken.
I see.
And anyway...
What is this fancy jacket?
How come you look
so smug and contented?
It's the ladies, old man.
It's the ladies.
You know how it is.
Ah, yes...
the ladies!
Then it's alright.
These things happen.
We'll come up with something.
No problem.
And now off you go, I'm busy.
Hey!
Give me the number!
Hello, so you took a look
at those documents?
Look, I don't want to waste time...
Oh, God...
I'm so sorry,
I'm so sorry!
Did you get your business done?
Yes.
Let's go somewhere inside
and get ourselves dry.
Don't be silly, I don't mean...
I must go home,
my parents will worry.
When will I see you?
Ten in the morning?
Ten o'clock?
I can't wait.
I'm so sorry.
What a dreadful city.
Why is it so dreadful?
I fear this is where
I'll meet my end.
I must go into town.
I see Kodor at ten.
Yes, of course,
you must go...
Although I wonder,
what's the point? I mean...
he only talks big.
The hell with Kodor.
I'm staying with you.
Well...
if that's
what you think...
Hey,
listen to this!
Two spinster cousins were living
together in a small town.
The younger had grown
tired of the other one.
She was in love, and...
the other cousin
kept pestering her.
So she poisoned her.
With nicotine.
Hmm...
Can you really kill someone
with nicotine that easily?
Yes.
Quite easily.
Poor thing.
Yes, it's an ugly story.
Just think. No one would
ever have found out,
but this silly girl
let it slip by accident.
But who are
you talking about?
What do you mean who?
Haven't you been listening?
Your point of view is rather
interesting, don't you think?
And why?
At last she could
have enjoyed her life.
In freedom.
But Lizzy...
you're talking about...
Come on... You just
don't want to understand.
You know what?
I'd rather go and see
Kodor after all.
Ah!
What happened?
My foot...
I have a terrible cramp.
Let me see it.
You're alive!
I dreamt of you last night,
and it was so terrible...
I just sat by a window and
wept for you. And...
then I arrived here,
I see this crowd,
standing around a body,
and you're still not here...
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry.
Last night,
when I woke up from
that dream,
I just sat and sat,
unable to fall asleep again.
And I thought it over, and
if you still want me to...
I'll go... to a hotel with you.
Don't...
Hey...
I love you so much...
but...
You're right.
I just realized what a heartless
creature I've become.
I wasn't always like this.
It's just...
Tell me,
will you be my wife?
Yes!
Yes, I will.
Do you really mean it?
Believe me,
I'd rather die than go on
the way I'm living now.
Take me as your wife,
but truly, marry me!
I will show you what
a good wife I'll be...
- Why are you cross now?
- Why would I be cross?
I'm not angry!
Anyway, it's not
my style to just get...
cross with someone.
I'm not one of your French hussies.
Hey!
Look here,
you're obviously angry
with me because of my wife.
That's really not fair.
And anyway...
why worry about her?
Soon I'll be divorced.
I told you that.
Ah... Divorce...
It's never an easy thing.
- Especially in such a case--
- Such as what?
You'll never be able
to break away from her.
No matter how much I love you.
You know why?
Because you're not like that.
You're like me.
You have a faithful heart.
Right now we have a party to go to.
I'm closing on
a fabulous deal, old man!
They all think I'm doing them a favour.
Can you believe that?
Mhm.
Come on now, out with it.
What is the matter with you?
I barely recognize you.
What are you talking about?
When?
Back then.
There, at the...
Mhm.
And did you really
marry the first woman...?
Yes.
How come you
never told me...?
You've got more guts than I thought.
Now let's get to business!
Help me and I'll make you rich!
Take it!
Be flashy tonight.
Look at him!
My oldest friend,
a real tough sea captain!
He can swig a tumblerful
in a single gulp!
Oh! Doesn't he have
an Adam's apple?
Doesn't he have a soul?
I intend to seduce you.
Mr. Kodor,
we would appreciate it if you...
once again summed
up the terms for our benefit.
Please, have some
consideration for the ladies...
let's not talk about business tonight.
I just wanted to say...
My dear gentlemen!
Let's not spoil this lovely
evening by talking business.
After all, we have agreed on
everything. Isn't that so?
In my opinion
a few points still remain...
- Please...
- Doctor...
Dear gentlemen!
I drink to the success of
our consortium!
Cheers!
So...
alright,
sign it there and there...
and we are done.
I told you,
I'll make you rich!
Kodor and Sons...
petrol consortium...
I didn't know
you had sons!
Well...
Not that I know of,
but it sound more classy this way.
Don't you find?
What is this, actually?
What is it, what is it...
What do you care?
You are just confirming
that no one had objections to
the conditions of the deal.
You know,
I want to cheat these people.
- Just a bit.
- But...
Aren't these people
going to be bankrupt?
And why should't they?
What a story!
So what are you?
A virgin?
Just say you do not want
to sign and that's that.
Alright.
Bravo.
Tell me your honest opinion,
do you believe in
a higher intelligence?
A higher?
What the hell
are you talking about?
But...
Don't you believe in the movement
of the stars, in a cosmic order?
Why must your kind
always bring up the stars!
Why not a carrot?
A carrot?
It's a miracle of nature
as much as a star!
Hello!
You are so sweet
when you're drunk!
Anyhow,
these two millionaire heiresses
I ran into at Kodor's...
One was like a vanilla cake,
and the other one
had a waist like a violin...
You're such a poet!
Both of them,
I swear to you...
proposed to me...
But how can I marry two of them
at the same time?
Didn't you let them know that
you already have a wife?
Of course I did!
They couldn't care less!
It's funny.
Only yesterday someone
proposed to me as well.
Would you let me go?
Sir, if you hire me
to gather evidence for divorce,
to catch the parties in flagrante,
that would be quite
a different rate...
than if you just want me to provide
a list of where, with whom,
and how many times Madame
is doing it.
Now...
if you also need the intimate details,
positions, accessories used in the act...
But...
I am not at all sure that
there is actually an act!
And do you really
want to know?
Sometimes it is better not to.
I simply would like to know
what she does all day.
Let me tell you something.
I have been doing it
for thirty years.
Trailing women has given me
flat feet and rheumatism.
You will never believe
what they are capable of.
In my experience, dear sir,
there is no such thing
as an innocent woman.
Jacques?
Yes?
Would you
button me up, please?
Lizzy, tell me sincerely,
who proposed to you
the other day?
What a big ninny you are!
I can't believe
you took me seriously,
I really can't believe it!
A quarter pound
of flour, please.
May I know
what you need it for?
What... why?
I'd like some flour.
Easy enough, isn't it?
Sir, we have nine
different types of flour.
Is it for leavened dough
or for puff-pastry?
Or perhaps for cooking?
That's it, cooking.
Hey!
Hey sweetheart!
Uhm...
Did I tell you that
I'm going to Bruges this evening?
Uhm... Yes!
Kodor finally came through... yes...
Uhm...
I'll be gone for two days.
So uhm...
See you in two days!
Bye!
Haven't you set out?
The trip was canceled.
Who's that?
Don't, please,
don't go!
Why shouldn't I?
Don't leave me alone!
Do you know who
knocked on our door?
Did you seen him?
I did.
So?
It was me.
Oh...
And why,
if I may ask?
Well, you took the front gate key
and didn't give it back.
Oh...
You're right!
And why do you need that lousy key
at the crack of dawn?
It's Friday!
So what?
I have to go to the market.
I'm late already.
They'll make me pay double
for everything, those robbers.
What's this mess here'?
What do you keep
in your pockets?
What do you mean?
This...
That... Uhm...
I'll let you guess what it is.
It's uhm...
It's a bit of cocaine.
And what do you need cocaine for?
Dear God...
I also need something
to make my life more bearable.
It's a bit of flour, it really is.
I wanted to sprinkle it
on the threshold
to find out who
climbs into our bed
when I'm not home.
Most peculiar...
The point is...
your wife seems
to be faithful to you.
She's a charming creature.
I can only congratulate you.
But, you know, I can continue
for half price for one more month,
lovers can have
longer absences, you know.
Just give me the bill
and we call this off.
They're beautiful!
Here you are.
Thank you!
You're turning into quite a gentleman!
You know that this is the first time
you buy me flowers?
I'll fill the vase with water.
Nice!
Are you alright?
You look like death...
Captain!
What an ho nor!
Your reputation precedes you!
A cigar?
I'm fine, thank you!
But enough chatter...
How can I be of service to you?
I'll get straight to the point.
I need work.
How come...
But, sure, sure,
it is a real ho nor you chose us!
Well, the Yasmin a
is leaving for Cape Town.
Carrying English broadcloth.
I can move the captain
to another ship...
you take his place.
No, the thing is...
I have to find some work on dry land.
Oh... I see. I'm truly sorry.
Illness in the family?
Something like that...
Fred!
Captain Störr has personal problems.
Do we have any work for him?
Please,
follow me, sir.
You're still up,
working?
Oh, my God.
You should see your eyes.
Why?
What do they look like?
They are so...
beady.
Are you angry at me?
I have certainly painted
the town red tonight...
I drank champagne...
I even had some port,
If you want to know...
Mhm.
So I'm a bit tipsy.
Do you have any idea how good
cigarette smoke and chocolate
taste together?
I learned that from a young man...
tonight.
Would you like to try it?
I kept one for you.
Together...
I'll leave it here.
I'm going to bed.
Would you like to join?
You're at work early today...
What is it for?
What do you mean, what is it for?
That's right,
I asked you what you need money for.
I'm having lunch in town today...
anyway, I have my expenses...
Why don't you eat
lunch at home?
Our meals are paid for.
That indeed is a most
important consideration.
Money isn't actually
pouring in at the moment.
In case you haven't noticed.
Well...
If you say so...
Ooops!
Have you had your fun?
What a clown...
This is the menu of the next week.
If there is anything you don't like,
- perhaps I can make some changes.
- All right, fine, thank you!
No, no, no, I read it out to you,
I don't have a copy!
I'll come down later.
At the moment...
Actually I didn't really
come up for the menu...
but in order to clear up
something about the carrots...
The what?
The... how do you say...
the eternal soul of a carrot.
Or of a cucumber.
Or a pipe...
I don't need to explain
to you your own idea.
Listen, my wife isn't feeling well...
Oh, why didn't you say so!
She's not expecting
something little, is she?
No, for God's sake!
Excuse me...
Finished, already.
You're always on time.
What happened
to these files?
I'm sorry.
Well,
don't worry,
everything is visible, and,
as much as I know you I'm sure,
it is flawlessy correct, as always.
Fine, your pay is due next week.
The thing is...
could I get paid today?
No, I'm afraid not.
Check back here in three days.
Good evening.
One bag, please.
With pleasure!
50 cents.
That's fine...
- Thank you!
- Have a nice evening!
Let's hope you don't get pneumonia...
Thank you.
So... All this story you told me...
How do you feel about it now?
It's just miserable.
Why?
I cannot even drown myself properly.
That's a good one.
No, but really,
tell me!
You tell me!
Tell me, why can't I create some...
order in my miserable little life?
Well,
who can...?
Apparently, almost everyone.
Have you ever seen a piglet?
What?
A soft little creature.
It starts to squeal when grabbed
by strangers who want to eat it.
Well, that's our lot on Earth,
more or less.
We squeal or not...
doesn't matter much.
Believe me, this world
is not made for us.
It's not made for our soul.
This is not it's home.
So, don't be surprised.
Do you realize how lucky you are?
You can simply get up and...
and leave all this misery behind!
It just doesn't work.
So what?
Yeah, you're
right. But...
I, for one, would do it
if I were in your place.
I would do it.
I imagine...
I'm already dead...
But before I die... I...
I revive for one last time, and...
and run away.
I...
I receive a brief reprieve,
somewhere,
a stranger cast up on
a strange shore.
And...
and isn't that what...
what life's all about?
Receiving one reprieve after another?
Jacques!
Hey there my big captain!
Come with me.
I'm on my way to a punch party.
Well...
How about spending a night
on the town instead?
There's an idea!
I can't attend tonight.
Please, apologize on my behalf,
say I've got a cold,
Guess what...?
I met someone!
He's...
He's handsome,
actually very handsome.
He's got blue eyes,
blonde hair,
broad shoulders...
He has this...
special something...
Well, I see
you tomorrow...
Jacques?
Madame!
May I accompany you?
I simply offer
a brief companionship.
Brief and passing.
After all, people get acquainted
in dance halls nowadays.
Then may I suggest you
try a dancehall.
Oh, please
have a heart.
Soon enough
I'll be gone forever,
far away,
to the end of the world...
You see I'm a sailor,
the captain of a ship.
But are you
really a captain?
Because you don't
look like one.
I don't look like one?
I've been here perhaps too long.
Whew, if you only knew what
I've gone through in this city...
Such as what?
Tell me, I'd really like to hear this.
My heart is so restless
my dear Madame,
I have a broken heart!
You're forgetting
one thing, sir.
And that is?
I happen to have a husband
whom I deeply love.
You love your husband?
What's so amazing
about that?
My God...
what kind of husband could he be?
What kind?
Well he's very nice.
But what I think is even
more important,
he's an honest man.
Damn...
a husband without a single fault?
Well...
he does have one.
He does have one.
He worries too much.
Why, you, for example...
are you faithful to him?
What a laughable question...
So charmingly stupid.
Of course I'm
faithful to him!
Didn't you know,
my dear Captain?
If you really are a captain...
Well...
then...
Come on,
you big silly thing.
You proposed to
take me somewhere.
My hands are getting cold.
Be careful!
You see,
you never courted me.
Courted you?
Yes...
courting is a must.
You know I could have died for you,
I loved you so much.
And that's over now?
Yes.
It's over now.
What a pity.
Yes.
A pity...
Or maybe not.
Perhaps it was too much.
Oh...
You're feverish...
Your head is burning up!
Get well!
Please get well!
You'll see, I'll behave myself.
What day is it?
Wednesday.
So I was ill for only two days...
Somehow it seemed longer.
It was indeed.
It's already April,
my dear.
Oh...
How pale you are?
What have we been living on?
I sold some of my jewelry.
It was difficult, wasn't it?
It was.
But it was beautiful.
This came a little while ago.
What is it?
The damn oil shares from Kodor.
Perhaps some day they'll make us rich.
What's that'?
A scent of melon?
No, it's linseed oil!
Yes, it is...
Perhaps you know something
about vegetable oils, my good man?
Oh, I certainly do.
Well, well...
Who would have thought?
Where are you from?
From a small village near Arnhem.
But it's a long time since
my childhood there.
A very long time.
Oh, interesting... that's where
my grandmother is from.
Which village exactly?
Rijjsen.
And I thought you were
some sort of Fleming!
My God, no!
I haven't been home
for thirty years either.
I'll have to die without having
tasted a good hut spot again...
And bitterballen...
Bitterballen, that's right.
With a tad of cinnamon
from Ceylon... or curry...
I need someone steady
on our East Indies line.
I am not interested in
short term solutions.
This is what
I am looking for.
Good.
It is the Jasmin a,
harboured in Cuxhaven...
you should set sail in a week.
It is all right, I hope?
I'd like to take my wife along.
Your wife?
Are you newlyweds or what?
Not exactly.
Or do you enjoy being with
your wife so much?
Yes.
It's so rare.
I tend to place more trust
in lucky people...
So...
You'll set sail for Java
in a week then.
Along with your wife.
Am I dreaming or what...?
Why don't you join us!
We go to a costume ball!
We are harem ladies and
we have no harem guard!
Thank you.
Lizzy?
Champagne?
Thank you.
Well, well, well...
We are sitting over there,
with Kodor.
Won't you come and see him?
The hell with him...
Do come, or he'll be angry with me.
Why not?
What a surprise...
Giacomo himself!
Why are you eating
by your lonesome self?
Got divorced, perhaps?
I am...
Yes, I did.
Oh...
We have to celebrate that!
Do you know The Salty Sea?
We are sailing for a seafarer's pay
Over the salty sea
Though there are never women on board
Over the large and briny sea,
Over the salty sea
And whether we're in a good mood or bad
We are driven by the wind
Over the large and briny sea,
Over the salty sea
And we will get drunk ashore,
The pour beer as bitter as bile
Over the large and briny sea,
Over the salty sea
And when we are gone forever,
over the salty sea
Very nice!
Very virile, indeed...
It's a pity your wife couldn't hear this.
I wonder what is she doing right now.
Have a nice trip!
Who were those people?
I have no idea.
Was my wife in that car?
Of course it was her.
I... I...
Where to?
Central station.
Captain...
Good morning!
Now hand over
those shares, please.
What shares?
The oil shares, what else.
Let's not create
a scene over this.
There's one more thing I need.
Here, I'll dictate.
With the help of my lover...
I stole these shares from you.
I'm sorry to admit...
I lived a dishonorable life.
Now sign it.
Forgive me!
I need it for the divorce.
Because I'm not gonna
pay any alimony.
If I had a son, what would I say
to him by way of farewell?
I would describe this morning,
maybe nothing else.
That should be enough...
One can't give advice anyway.
I would talk to him
about evanescence...
That life is nothing more
than playful variations.
That it is useless to look
for something sublime behind it:
a planned purpose
or a superior aim,
because there is
nothing behind it.
Because just as the light
slips away above us,
in the same way life
slips away within us.
So what would I say to my son?
That he should learn to appreciate
this eternal procession...
and not oppose it with all
his strength as I did at one time.
Then he'll become the sort
of creature God had intended.
One who lives easily,
and passes on easily.
- Hello?
- Good morning, Madame.
- I'm an old acquaintance...
- Ah, is that you, Captain?
How nice to hear your voice.
I recognized it right away!
Do you remember that evening
at the cafe when we first met?
Believe it or not,
I even remember what we drank that evening.
As a matter of fact,
I would like to...
And Lizzy, poor thing,
how sweet she was that evening...
what a delightful little creature she was...
Tell me, do you still think of her,
the poor dear?
Why do you keep saying
"the poor dear"?
You've said it twice,
I don't understand.
She doesn't seem miserable...
I saw her in the street today.
She didn't look like
she'd aged at all...
But...
Sorry, but...
who are you talking about?
Who do you think?
I must tell you, seeing her
in that little black coat,
it was funny because,
you don't see that straight style
nowadays at all, but...
her figure was the same as ever...
But, tell me, was the coat
closed at the neck?
Yes, it was closed...
And trimmed with fur?
Yes, yes...
a light-colour fur.
Oh, God,
then it must have been her.
Because I sent her that coat from Paris,
just before she died...
I beg your pardon?
Didn't you know?
Is it possible you didn't know
that the sweet dear has passed away?
Six years ago now...
But that's wonderful you see,
how lucky you are...
What a shining little guest
you had today!
And what a bright little
companion she was...
while she lived beside you!
She appeared to you today.
After all,
she loved you so much.